

GÃűteborg, Sweden +46 (0)720 130 370 wouter.dankers@skynet.be github.com/DankersW

Languages

Dutch

English

French

Swedish

Interests

(or life	Ic	Ice-hockey			
				gSurfing		
S	Skiing IoT			Automation		
	Natu		ıre]	Robotics	
		Smart-cities				

Wouter Dankers

System Engineer

About me I am an experienced and versatile software engineer that takes great pride in writing well functioning and clean code that scales and ages well. I am organized, open minded, and efficient, with attention to detail and I have excellent people skills.

Experience

Jun 2018 - present, Volvo Group GÃűteborg, Sweden

System Engineer

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016, Memory x design Beijing, China

Internship

Tech stack

o C++ Docker Git o micro-Python Embedded-Jenkins services Bash Systems Automation Wireless C-ITS GCP IoT communi- Networking Agile cation Linux

Education

2016 - 2018, Halmstad University Halmstad, Sweden

MSc. Embedded and Intelligent systems

2013 - 2016, Thomas More Hogeschool Geel, Belgium

BSc. ICT and Telecommunication

Hobby projects

Home automation

Topics: Google cloud platform, ESP32, IoT, Python, Monitoring Self developed home automation kit that runs on a local server as well as in the cloud. The cloud service is mostly used for natural language processing (voice commands using Google Assistant) and an integration with the Sonos ecosystem. The home server serves as a device gateway, storage facility, and as a monitoring unit in the form of a web-server.

DIY drone

Topics: Robotics, Wireless communication, Python, Gyroscope Powerful lifting drone that was completely build from scratch including the remote controller, stabilisation algorithm and control software.

Work achievements

Volvo Group

Verification platform: Redesigned how Bitbucket events trigger Jenkins jobs, and how the CI-CD chain is build-up. Kafka was used as message queue between several created Dockerized micro services written in Python that were spread out over the Volvo network. I designed the system from a conceptional idea to a production ready implementation. The project is used by the verification department of the Connectivity Group.

DevOps Engineer: Created and maintained several CI-CD freestyle Jenkins jobs (Python) as part of the CI team responsible for the telematics gateway.

Data logging system: Prototyped and developed (C++) a data logging system for autonomous and concept vehicles. Including hardware selection, embedded software, design of an on- and off-board QUI, data storage, as well as remote controlling of the logging unit.

Scrum master: Scrum master on the agile release train that created the first commercial autonomous transportation solution.

Communication infrastructure to enable autonomous driving: Investigating the requirements, selection of Hardware and technologies, as well as on-site measurements. Later on I became the element owner of the wireless communication infrastructure at the project's customer.

Research projects: Software Developer (C++) on public funded research projects with a focus on C-ITS.

Master thesis

Learning wireless channels models to design real-time communications: Co-authored a research paper based on the results of my master thesis. The Paper got published in IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology

Memory x design

Prototyped the next phase of the customers product road-map.